you could say something about the and
what the characteristics of the Dumber
you know when someone who sees the
Dhamma sees that are this dumber is
Sunday so first of all I mean you've
said something about SWAT oh well
expounded or as well this is right well
told it's means things like its it is to
be experienced know it can be understood
in this very life oh it's timeless
principle well yeah you can literally
mean anything for people as and that's
the case with any suitors as well you
can take them to be like a poetic
inspiration oh you can assume did they
mean something much more accurately by
the way you you have to approach with
the assumption what they are for and
what the purpose is and what they mean
so then if you are self transparent and
if you have some decent habit of self
reflection you would question your
assumption you got to it so say you
assume suitors to mean you know kind of
loose folklore poetic inspiration of you
know talking about the life that's worth
living that's correct
in a way yeah you can take them to mean
that but then if you start to read the
same suitors you get to find out that if
you were to understand what a Buddhist
teaching you will be free from suffering
you will be fully enlightened so then
you revise your assumption what suitors
are and what they mean and see whether
your current understanding and nobody
denies there is some understanding of it
is that making you another hunt or is
that making a sort of honor or not as in
like right here right now do I have
results of this understanding not like
well I'm not yet but I know I will
how do you know that if you're not yet
so then if you if you if you see that
you don't have something to show for so
to speak you're not free from suffering
you don't know way out of the escape out
of there isn't suffering then you need
to reevaluate your assumption and then
it is ok so now consequently what if I
were to assume that suitors mean much
more accurate things than this romantic
poetic inspiration and then you you
approach them in that manner and then
which means correspondingly you have to
make that amount of effort to understand
it and then you get to see that you'll
be free from suffering and nothing has
changed even back in the day you
understand the Buddhist discus you know
soda pan or another so today you
understand it what is this could be also
about another hunt if you're not missed
cuz you haven't understood it so same
goes for the term makovica okay give me
in timeless and you know it's it's
beyond time it will ask for it seems
like glancing and really something to
strive for anybody can understand that
does that understanding they cannot hunt
or a sort upon at least because again so
to say that if you understand the Dharma
the characteristics of the Dharma means
you understand the world of suffering
means you at least have the right view
so when you think you understood what a
colic means he's there all right view
arising as a result of it so that's the
questioning a person should do and if
there is no review means the
understanding is not adequate
so without that self-reflection there is
no really
base for communication it's just gonna
be well that's what the means this for
me and you might need something else for
you and that's fine but if you're honest
yourself you know as well not both of us
cannot be right because there are two
different meanings and different people
can have a different understanding of
what color means well exactly because
yeah the Buddha was not just throwing
these understandings for the sake of
understanding he was teaching him
because they result in the freedom from
suffering and even when sometimes the
Buddha was talking about things that are
indirectly related to the Dhamma even
that he was actually related to some
purpose he was making some point he was
making for the sake of freedom from
suffering when he was talking about a
previous slide for future lives at
different places of rebirth he was in
the context of people were listening for
whom that will cause sense of urgency
so they'll practice in this life he was
on you know giving a social commentary
on them on the current Brahmin caste
system or something it's irrelevant
suffering and freedom from it is the
only purpose of his entire teaching 40
years could you say it wasn't really
explaining anything absolutely no
explanation here yeah it's not it's
describing something you need to see for
yourself yeah if I explain it to you you
can take it or leave it
yeah either way you won't get it yeah
because you think now explanation is
what I was talking about so I can
explain to you four noble truths and you
can make perfect sense out of it and yet
you're still not free from suffering but
instead I could describe Four Noble
Truths abstain from explaining it to you
and and then you will have to recognize
or rather there is a better chance of
recognizing then oh this is something
that I need to see for myself in order
to fully to be understood I cannot
no yes I know but Four Noble Truths
ah and at the same time I know that I'm
not free from suffering that is mutually
exclusive if you know what fun / truth
are you are free from suffering and I
mean I can explain to you and if you're
self transparent you will not take that
explanation wrongly you will know where
to apply but most people especially ones
with the other right view which is vast
majority they don't know that and
immediately explanation immediately
means oh I have made sense out of it
that's understood it and that's why
that's that it's well expounded that
first categories it means that it will
the Buddha was the foremost in
expounding the Dhamma knew how to teach
you or the audience without making a
jump into assumption that they
understood that which they didn't so he
would lead them onwards towards the
right understanding and you know that's
a skill in itself but it does always
require the other party to meet you
halfway
so it's leading on the top and I cut
it's not meeting its the translation of
anything in words well if you're a sort
of tree hugging flower lovin with this
spiritualist I mean you have anything in
words okay it's basically please don't
lead you in words to your heart or
something but what understanding horizon
kind of it is then are you saying that
output is the problem
so basically root of your suffering are
things that are out there in the world
well that's not what the bill said so
leading inward reading out words doesn't
matter in and out in enough like in or out both
in and out in enough like in or out both
in and out none of that contains the
problem it's a craving in regard to in what
it's a craving in regard to in what
you're craving is you got 12 words
you're craving in regard to both that's
why we suffer why you choose the
translator is leading in words and again
it would be like a beautiful feeding
verse and that's it there's nothing else
for you to do there you made sense out
of it makes you feel good then you think
okay I understood what I meant by this
and at the same time I know I'm still
not so dependent but I must be at some
point in the future because look all
these things want to come down more
pleasing me it means I must be doing
them rightly so a calico means Thomas
means not pertaining to time not
involving time
would you be able to sit here talk to me
without your body being that alive at
the same time was your body aligned
before so now your mind is here
communicating with me was my body alive
before yeah
but then is your mind to now result of
your body being a lot before you can't
know that and even if you say yes it is
is there a more accurate way of
describing the relationship well it
seems to me
yes that's any notion of what my body
was doing before secondary to the father
was a body here right now are there so
that I mean so even though the commonly
misunderstood causation between this is
first and this is the result of it it's
actually already contained within the
causation of that simultaneous presence
yes timeless present yes present that
doesn't require time to pass so you can
see yes I'm talking to you because if I
were an alive yesterday or this morning
I wouldn't be able to talk here today to
you that's absolutely right but it's not
accurate enough even more accurately you
can say if I'm not alive right here
right now if this heart is not beating
right here right now
lungs breathing right here right now I
could not talk to you right here right
now which is what I'm doing yeah and if
I couldn't imagine the past I can't
imagine the future how can you remember
your love yesterday except on the basis
of being alive today yeah but it's that
wrong order that you put your memory
first so because it's this basically
view of linear kind of persistence
through time like we are in time time is
this entity and we are just sort of
occupying it and flowing through it
which is kind of what I am what do you
mean there's this like this notion of
myself hmm as being this something
that's traveling through so Jonsey put
that first and you because you can take
the notion of yourself you remember when
you were a kid yeah when he was slightly
older when you're an adult you remember
now and yes you can choose to focus on
these individual aspects that have
changed yes but how would you even know to
yes but how would you even know to
relate them unless there is a certain
unity that still persists how would you
then connect memory of you in the past
with memory today you would simply be
inconceivable unless there is a unifying
basis of your Center so so can you say
that you
it's about discerning the necessary base
is something which is more encompassing
this time yeah but give me a prey for
example my body just mindfulness of the
body do you reckon like kind of putting
that you have the idea so somebody hears
this now okay so I'll practice
mindfulness to the body to develop this
simultaneous principle that these monks
keep talking about yeah see that idea
already is secondary to the body being
yes you're already within the
simultaneous principle even before you
make the effort to understand it how can
you think I'll practice mindfulness of
the body without that base of the body
being they provided for yourself as a
possibility impossible
which means with that body they're
already enduring there is your practice
of mindfulness or practice of non
mindfulness depending which way you go
so with this this is so that woman even
linear pursuits one two three four five
this is the cause this is the result
trying to figure it out he's secondary
it's dependent upon the simultaneously
during life or body or any other SP
really any other aggregate you want to
take and that's what Buddha meant when
he described the five aggregates when he
came to the aid of Sankara what is that
and then he describes five aggregates
again so whichever way you look it's the
five aggregates they depend on the five
aggregates which is why you can look at
them and attend to them and Accardo that
and so on it's all within their
dependence and that dependence is not at
all time because the notion of duration
which is what the notion of time is it's
already within that dependence on those
same aggregates other
have no notion of duration because
there's no reference point
so that's what like simultaneous
principal we talked about it it does not
mean you look at the two things that are
simultaneously or look at this and this
you left yourself out simultaneous
principle means where this is a basis
this is the experience so with this this
is so with this there is the being of
this whichever way you want to translate
it both are in the present tense well
yeah you can also say well it's not in
that immediate present tense it's in the
present tense of this life or something
sure but then ask yourself in the
beginning like what I said you should
ask yourself does that understanding
result in direct inability to suffer a
mid suffering no because anybody can
take it or leave it
Oh potato pot applies to this life for
three lines of six five plus twenty
several lives but there's dead
understanding for you from suffering no
so how about you then try to understand
it in a way that would free from
suffering because the Buddha said that
himself the one who understands but it's about
the one who understands but it's about
understands the Dhamma one who
understands the Dom understands but it's
nobody sees it for himself directly as a
result of which he cannot suffer so that
you mean there are no alternative
entertainer it's a father it's the
principle of the Dhamma that if
understood results in you being unable
to suffer emits suffering and that's
another thing that is principle by the
way with suffering non suffering not or
with suffering later I don't suffer that
management that psychotherapy now with
suffering present I don't suffer oh if
you if you haven't understood a
simultaneous principle with suffering
present I suffer
it's like anything is situated within
not anything you are yeah okay when I
say anything about anything I can
experience but yes yeah which is already
based on your situated experience you
are always in a situation always which
means there is always the present
enduring feeling yeah president during
intentions does knee during perceptions
always what do you see that